LIVE CLASSES

 SHOP

===============================================================================================================================================================================================

 LIVE CLASSES

 SHOP

**Unplug: Meditation App Privacy Policy**

Welcome to our Privacy Policy.  We provide guided meditation services through our suite of online services and mobile and web applications.

The Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose, and secure information we obtain through the “Site.”  The terms “**Unplug**,” “**we**,” and “**us**” include Unplug Meditation LLC and our affiliates and subsidiaries.  This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into our Terms of Use. Any capitalized terms used and not defined in this Privacy Policy shall have the meaning given to them in the Terms of Use.

The “**Site**” means any website, mobile application, or Internet service under the control of Unplug, whether partial or otherwise, in connection with providing an online platform for Unplug’s services.

“**Personal Information**” means information that alone or when in combination with other information may be used to readily identify, contact, or locate you, such as: name, address, email address, phone number, birthdate, and a profile photo (if you choose to upload one from your device and allow permission for the Site to access your device’s photo gallery).

**THE SITE COLLECTS YOUR INFORMATION**

**Registration and Account Information.**  To access most features of the Site, you must register for an account. To register, you may need to provide information about yourself, such as your email address, password, and your first and last name.  You may also provide other optional information, such as your city, state, and country.

**Social Connect.**  When you choose to log-in and connect your social media account to your Site profile, we collect information about you from that social media website.  For example, when you log-in with your Facebook account, we use your Facebook ID to authenticate you. We may also obtain other non-public information from social media websites with your permission.  

**Using the Site.**  We collect information you provide through the Site.  For example, you may choose to provide your personal meditation goals, short text bio, journal entries, nickname, birthdate, and a photo/avatar.

**Information and Content that You Select from Your Device.**  With your permission, the Site may access and collect information you select from your device’s photo storage so you can upload a photo or avatar to the Site. 

**1\. Information We Collect:**

1.1 Image Information:

When you use our app, we may collect and process the image information you upload. This includes photos, images, or any other visual content you choose to share within the app.

**2\. Use of Information:**

2.1 Purpose:

We collect and use your image information to provide you with the services and features of our app. The primary purpose of collecting your image information is to enable you to upload and share visual content within the app.

2.2 App Functionality:

We may also use your image information to enhance the functionality of the app, such as by enabling profile pictures or customizing user experiences within the app.

2.3 Aggregated and Anonymized Data:

We may aggregate and anonymize your image information for statistical analysis and to improve our app's performance, features, and services. This aggregated and anonymized data does not personally identify you.

**3\. Sharing of Information:**

3.1 Legal Compliance:

We may disclose your image information if required by law or if we believe such action is necessary to comply with legal obligations, protect our rights or the rights of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

**4\. Data Retention:**

We retain your image information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy or as required by law. If you choose to delete your account, please note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes, such as resolving disputes, enforcing our agreements, or detecting and preventing fraud.

**5\. Security:**

We take reasonable and appropriate measures to protect your image information from unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction. However, please be aware that no method of transmission over the internet or electronic storage is completely secure, and we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your data.

**6\. Your Rights:**

You have the right to access, correct, update, or delete your image information. You can exercise these rights by:

* Open App
    
* Click Profile Icon
    
* Click Pencil Icon
    
* Click Avatar 

If you have any questions or need further assistance regarding your rights, please email us at support@unplug.com.

**Making Payments.**  When you make payments through the Site, you will need to provide financial account information, such as your credit card number, Apple account payment information or Google account payment information, to our third-party service providers.  We do not collect or store such information, though we will receive information about completed transactions that does not include credit card or bank account numbers.

**Communicate with Us.**  We collect information about you through your communications with our customer-support team or through other communications with us, including through social media.

**From Other Sources.**  We may receive information about you from third parties.  We may combine this information with other information about you that we received through the Site. 

**Automatic Data Collection: Cookies and Related Technologies.**  When you visit our Site or open our emails, we and our third-party partners, such as advertising networks, social media widgets, and analytics providers, collect certain information by automated means, such as cookies, web beacons and web server logs. By using the Site, you consent to the placement of cookies, beacons, and other similar technology in your browser and on emails in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  The information collected in this manner includes IP address, browser characteristics, device IDs and characteristics, operating system version, language preferences, referring URLs, and information about the usage of our Site. We may use this information, for example, to determine how many users have visited certain pages or opened messages or newsletters, or to prevent fraud.  We may link this data to your profile.  Our partners also may collect and combine information collected on our Site and emails with other information about your online activities over time, on other devices, and on other websites or apps, if those websites and apps also use the same partners.  We currently use Google Analytics to collect and process certain website usage data.  To learn more about Google Analytics and how to opt out, please visit www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.  You may be able to change browser settings to block and delete cookies when you access the Site through a web browser.  However, if you do that, the Site may not work properly.  The Site does not respond to browser do-not-track signals.

**HOW UNPLUG USES YOUR INFORMATION**

**Internal and Service-Related Usage.**  We use information for internal and service-related purposes.  We may use and retain any data we collect to provide and improve any of our services.

**Communications.**  We may send emails to the email address you provide to us, and push notifications to your mobile device if you have downloaded our app and enabled notifications, to verify your account and for informational and operational purposes, such as account management, customer service, system maintenance, and other Site-related purposes.

**Marketing.**  We may use information about you for marketing purposes, such as providing online advertising on the Site and sending you information we think may be useful or relevant to you.  You may opt out of email marketing by using the unsubscribe link in a marketing email.

**Aggregate Data.**  We anonymize or aggregate data collected through the Site and may use and disclose it for any purpose.

**UNPLUG MAY DISCLOSE YOUR INFORMATION**

**We Use Vendors and Service Providers.**  We share information we receive with vendors and service providers that perform services for us.  For example, through our Site, you provide information to payment processors as part of financial transactions, and we will share your information with service providers, such as web and database hosting services. 

**Displaying to Other Users.**  The information and content you provide to the Site may be displayed on the Site.  Other users of the Site may be able to see some information about you, such as your bio, photo/avatar, and your city, state, and country.  We are not responsible for how other users will view and use the posted information.

**Information Shared with Other Systems.** You may instruct us to share certain of your information with systems such as Apple’s HealthKit or Google Fit, and to access information from those systems which we will use to improve the services we provide to you. Before you tell us to share your information with another system, however, you should review the applicable privacy policy of that system, since any information you have instructed us to share will become subject to those policies (i.e. Apple’s policies or Google’s policies). In addition, in the event that you use one of those services, you should be careful about allowing other applications, services or people to access your information through that service. While much information collected by those services is innocuous, people who see Unplug data may be able to determine a variety of personal information.

* Unplug does not use or disclose to third parties user data or other information gained through the use of the HealthKit framework or Google Fit for advertising, other use- based data mining purposes or similar services, other than for purposes of improving health or for purposes of health or medical research.
    
* In the case of information gained through HealthKit or Google Fit such sharing will only be for purposes of enabling the third party to provide health and/or fitness services or for medical research.
    
* We do not sell any of your information, including information gained through HealthKit or Google Fit, to advertising platforms, data brokers or information resellers.
    
* We do not use any of the information obtained through HealthKit or Google Fit for any purpose other than providing health and/or fitness services in connection with the Services.

**Information Shared with Third Party Rewards Programs**. If you review or redeem a third party offer for a trial subscription to the Site, we may share your information (such as your first and last name, email address, and the fact that you signed up for a trial subscription to the Site) with such third parties. These third parties may use your information for their business purposes in accordance with their privacy policies, such as analyzing who took advantage of their offer, and for other related purposes.

**Social Networking Websites.**  The Site may allow you to share information with social networking websites, such as Facebook.  Their use of the information will be governed by their privacy policies, and we are not responsible for how they treat the information.

**Marketing and Advertising Partners.**  We do not rent, sell, or share personal information (as defined by California Civil Code §1798.83) about you that we collect on the Site with other people or unaffiliated companies for their direct marketing purposes, unless we have your permission. 

**Legal and Similar Disclosures**.  We may access, preserve, and disclose your information, if we believe doing so is required or appropriate to: comply with law enforcement requests and legal process, such as a court order or subpoena; respond to your requests; comply with the law; or protect your, our, or others’ rights, property, or safety.

**Merger, Sale, or Other Asset Transfers.**  If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, sale of company assets, or transition of service to another provider, your information may be disclosed in connection with the negotiation of such transaction, and/or sold or transferred as part of such a transaction as permitted by law and/or contract.  

**With Your Permission.**  We may also disclose your information with your permission.

**CLOSING YOUR ACCOUNT**

You have the right to request, under certain circumstances, the closing/deactivation of your account. We keep some of your information even after you close your account. If you choose to close your account, your Personal Information will generally not be available to others on the Site. We generally delete closed account information within 30 days of account closure, except as described below.

We retain your Personal Information even after you have closed your account (but it is not available through the Site) if we think it is reasonably necessary to allow you to restart your account, comply with our legal obligations and law enforcement requests, resolve disputes, maintain security, prevent fraud and abuse, and enforce our Terms of Use. We will also retain anonymized information about you after your account has been closed. Our back-up systems may also retain residual copies of your deleted Personal Information due to the nature of those systems’ operations.

Information you have shared with others (e.g., through comments) will remain visible after you close your account, but we will no longer identify you on the Site in association with such shared information.  We do not control and are not responsible for information that other users copied out of the Site.

**DELETING YOUR ACCOUNT**

You have the right to request, under certain circumstances, the deletion of your account and all personal information tied to it. Please submit account deletion requests to support@unplug.com so we can assist you in a timely manner.

On devices running iOS or iPadOS, there is also the option for account deletion within the mobile app under Profile > Settings > Delete Account. Selecting this option will completely remove your account from our database, and this action is not reversible.

**INFORMATION SECURITY**

We take steps in an effort to treat your information securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  Unfortunately, the Internet cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you provide to us.

**CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use personal information from children under 13 years of age.  Parents may create accounts on behalf of their children, and in those cases, parents represent and warrant that they, and not their children, are providing any personal information of a child. If you learn that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, you may alert us at support@unplug.com.  If we learn that we have collected any personal information from children under 13, we will promptly take steps to delete such information and terminate the child’s account.

**INTERNATIONAL USERS**

**If you are using the Site, you agree to the transfer of your information to the United States and processing globally. By providing your information you consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Privacy Policy.**

**UPDATE YOUR INFORMATION OR POSE A QUESTION OR SUGGESTION**

If you would like to request that we update or correct any information that you have provided to us through your use of the Site or otherwise, or if you have suggestions for improving this Privacy Policy, please send an email to support@unplug.com. If you are under the age of 18 and a California resident, you may request that content or information you posted to the Site no longer be publicly accessible from the Site by sending an email to support@unplug.com. After completing the request, we may continue to hold your content and information and such content and information may remain publicly available if your association with the content and information is removed or another user posted, copied, or re-posted the content and information.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY AND PRACTICES**

**Posting of a Revised Privacy Policy**

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time, and the revised version will be effective when it is posted. If we make any material changes, we will let you know through the Site, by email, or other communication. We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy periodically to stay up-to-date about our privacy practices. As long as you use the Site, you are agreeing to this Privacy Policy and any updates we make to it.

**California Privacy Rights**

Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us once a calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses.  If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information shared, the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year, and descriptions of the likely types of marketing the third parties would send. Unplug does not engage in this type of sharing with third parties.

To make a request, please send an email message to support@unplug.com or mail us at the address below with “Request for California Privacy Information” on the subject line and in the body of your message.  If you are a California resident, we will provide the requested information to you at your e-mail address in response.

Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the “Shine the Light” requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response.

**Contact Information**

Unplug Meditation LLC

12401 Wilshire Blvd. #101

Los Angeles, CA 90025

support@unplug.com

**Last Updated:** May 25, 2023

### Unplug Meditation

12401 Wilshire Boulevard, Suite 101 Los Angeles, CA 90025

(310) 826-8899

### [About](https://www.unplug.com/about-1)

[FAQs](https://www.unplug.com/faqs)﻿

### Unplug App

### Find A Class

### [Classes](https://www.unplug.com/classes)

### [Get Our Apps](https://www.unplug.com/get-our-apps)

### [Shop](https://www.unplug.com/shop)

### [Careers](https://www.unplug.com/careers)

### [Accessibility](https://www.unplug.com/accessibility)

### [Contact US](https://www.unplug.com/contact-us-virtual)

Subscribe for the Unplug scoop
------------------------------

Be the first to know about exclusive classes & offers. Subscribe to our mailing list.

Email Address 

Sign Up

We respect your privacy! By opting in, you agree to the terms outlined in our [Privacy Policy](https://unplug.com/privacy-policy).

Thank you!

Unplug Meditation, 12401 Wilshire Boulevard, Suite 101, Los Angeles, CA 90025(310) 826-8899[info@unplugmeditation.com](mailto:info@unplugmeditation.com)

© 2024 Unplug Meditation
